K7空间站已进入传感器范围，舰长
Deep Space Station K-7 now within sensor range, captain.
很好
Good.
契科夫，本次航行目的是锻炼船员，增长见识
Mr. Chekov, this flight is supposed to provide experience and knowledge.
如果我们保持这一航线前进
How close will we come to the Klingon outpost
我们将距离克林贡前哨有多近？
if we continue on our present course?
1秒差距，长官，几乎可以闻到他们
One parsec, sir. Close enough to smell them.
这不合逻辑，少尉
That is illogical, ensign.
在真空环境下气味无法传播
Odours cannot travel through the vacuum of space.
- 我只是开了个小玩笑，长官 - 太小了，少尉
- I was making a little joke, sir. - Extremely little, ensign.
史波克，近代史中是如何描述这一象限的
Mr. Spock, immediate past history of the quadrant.
自从初步接触后，这里一直都是两派的争议地带
Under dispute between the two parties since initial contact.
23个太阳年前，多纳图V星战役
The battle of Donatu V was fought near here
就发生在这附近，这场战役不分胜负
23 solar years ago. Inconclusive.
- 对此争议地区的分析 - 尚不明确
- Analysis of disputed area. - Undeveloped.
我们联邦和克林贡帝国
Sherman's Planet is claimed by both sides,
都对舍曼星球宣布了主权
our Federation and the Klingon Empire.
而且我们的更具优势
We do have the better claim.
这一区域最早是在200年前由著名的俄罗斯宇航员
The area was first mapped
伊万·伯科夫测绘标注的
by the famous Russian astronomer, lvan Burkoff, almost 200...
- 约翰·伯克 - 长官，伯克？
- John Burke. - Burke, sir?
我认为不对，我敢肯定就是
I don't think so. I'm sure it was...
约翰·伯克是当时大不列颠
John Burke was the chief astronomer
皇家学院首席宇航员
at the Royal Academy in Old Britain at the time.
皇家学院，那，好吧
Royal Academy, oh, well.
你其余的历史知识都是这么错漏百出吗，少尉？
Is the rest of your history that faulty, ensign?
争议的焦点是什么
Key points of dispute.
根据安根尼和平条约
Under the terms of the Organian Peace Treaty,
必须要向对方证明对星球进行了最有效的开发
one side or the other must prove it can develop the planet most efficiently.
不幸的是，虽然克林贡人野蛮且暴力
And unfortunately, though the Klingons are brutal and aggressive,
但他们的确进行了最有效的开发
they are most efficient.
我记得彼得大帝也曾遇到过同样的问题，而他
I remember once Peter the Great had a problem like that. He...
- 舰长 - 寇克
- Captain. - Kirk here.
舰长，紧急频道接收到一条子空间求救信号
Captain, I'm picking up a subspace distress call, priority channel.
- 是从K-7空间站发来的 - 曲速6前往
- It's from Space Station K-7. - Go to warp factor 6.
一级紧急电码那可是灾难救援呼叫
Code 1 emergency, that's a disaster call.
红色警戒，进入战备状态，全员待命
This is a red alert. Man your battle stations. All hands.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：茶包泰迪
校对：喜马拉雅
第二季第十五集
「毛球危机」
舰长日志，星历4523.3
Captain's log, stardate 4523.3.
K-7深空空间站发出了一级紧急电码
Deep Space Station K-7 has issued a priority- 1 call.
比紧急情况还严重，它代表“即将或已经面临重大灾难”
More than an emergency, it signals near or total disaster.
我们只能推测空间站遭到克林贡攻击
We can only assume the Klingons have attacked the station.
我们全副武装，准备即将到来的战斗
We're going in, armed for battle.
主相位炮已经准备就绪，长官
Main phasers armed and ready, sir.
但是除了空间站
But there's nothing there.
没有发现任何目标
Just the station.
发出一级求救信号，却一片风平浪静
Priority-1 distress call. It's just absolutely peaceful.
乌呼拉上尉，解除子空间缄默
Lieutenant Uhura, break subspace silence.
是，长官，频道打开，长官
Aye, sir. Channel's open, sir.
K-7空间站，这里是进取号舰长寇克
Space Station K-7, this is Captain Kirk of the Enterprise.
你们遇到了什么紧急情况？
What is your emergency?
寇克舰长，这里是K-7的负责人卢瑞
Captain Kirk, this is Mr. Lurry, manager of K-7.
我为之前发出求救信号表示抱歉
I must apologise for the distress call.
卢瑞，你发出了一级求救信号
Mr. Lurry, you issued a priority-1 distress call.
请对你面临的紧急情况予以说明
State the nature of your emergency.
或许你最好还是传送过来，我尽量向你解释
Well, perhaps you better beam over. I'll try to explain.
你尽量解释？
You'll try to explain?
你最好准备的再充分些，寇克
You'd better be prepared to do more than that. Kirk out.
史波克，我需要你跟我走，契科夫，保持战备状态
Mr. Spock, I'll need your help. Chekov, maintain battle readiness.
乌呼拉上尉，通知传送室待命
Lieutenant Uhura, see that the Transporter Room is standing by.
是，长官，传送室，准备待命
Aye, sir. Transporter Room, stand by.
卢瑞，如果没有任何紧急情况
Mr. Lurry, if there was no emergency,
你为什么要发出一级求救信号呢？
why did you issue a priority-1 distress call?
是我要求他这么做的，舰长
That was my order, captain.
寇克舰长，这位是尼兹·巴利斯，来自地球
Captain Kirk, this is Nilz Baris. He's out from Earth to take charge
是舍曼星负责人
of the development for Sherman's Planet.
所以你就有权拉响整个象限的警报？
And that gives you the authority to put an entire quadrant on defence alert?
巴利斯先生是联邦
Mr. Baris is the Federation undersecretary
在这一象限农业事务部的副部长
in charge of agricultural affairs in this quadrant.
这样的话他确实有这个权力
And that gives him the authority.
这是我的助理安恩·达尔文
This is my assistant, Arne Darvin.
- 这是我的大副，史波克 - 史波克先生
- And this is my first officer, Mr. Spock. - Mr. Spock.
舰长，我需要你船上的全部警卫
And now, captain, I want all available security guards.
我要他们在储藏室周围警戒
I want them posted around the storage compartments.
储藏室？器材室？
Storage compartments? Storage compartments?
储藏室里存有小黑麦
The storage compartments containing the quadrotriticale.
什么东西？小什么？什么是小黑麦？
The what? The what? What's quadrotriticale?
这个
Here.
麦子，那又怎么样？
Wheat. So what?
小黑麦不是麦子，舰长
Quadrotriticale is not wheat, captain.
当然，我没指望你或者史波克知道这是什么
Of course, I wouldn't expect you or Mr. Spock to know about such things,
小黑麦是非常
but quadrotriticale is a rather...
小黑麦是一种高产谷物
Quadrotriticale is a high-yield grain,
是小麦和裸麦杂交出的四向叶植物
a four-lobed hybrid of wheat and rye.
如果我没记错的话还是多年生作物
A perennial, also, if I'm not mistaken.
而它的本源黑小麦
Its root grain, triticale, can trace its ancestry
甚至可以追述到20世纪加拿大
all the way back to 20th-century Canada, where...
史波克，你说的挺清楚的了
Mr. Spock, you've made your point.
小黑麦是舍曼星唯一一种可以种植的地球谷物
Quadrotriticale is the only Earth grain that will grow on Sherman's Planet.
我们这个空间站目前有几吨的存储
Now, we have several tons of it here on the station
确保这批谷物顺利运送到舍曼星对我们来说非常重要
and it's very important that that grain get to Sherman's Planet safely.
巴利斯先生认为克林贡间谍会借机会进行破坏
Mr. Baris thinks that Klingon agents may try to sabotage it.
你发出一级求救信号就为了这么几吨麦子？
You issued a priority-1 distress call for a couple of tons of wheat?
是小黑麦
Quadrotriticale.
当然，舰长，我意识到我们这么做
Of course, captain, I realise that we...
巴利斯，没有紧急情况你却擅自召集进取号前来
Mr. Baris, you summoned the Enterprise without an emergency.
- 你将为此承担全部责任 - 你什么意思？
- You'll take full responsibility for it. - What do you mean?
滥用一级求救信号是联邦重罪
Misuse of the priority-1 channel is a Federation offence.
我没有滥用一级求救信号
I did not misuse the priority-1 channel.
我希望这批谷物收到相应的保护
I want that grain protected.
舰长，你能不能至少派一些安保人员过来？
Captain, couldn't you at least post a couple of guards?
我们这个空间站来往船只实在是太多了
We do have a large number of ships passing through.
舰长，这是一个符合逻辑的预防措施
It would seem a logical precaution, captain.
舍曼星球的事务对联邦来说也是至关重要的
The Sherman's Planet affair is of extreme importance to the Federation.
- 寇克呼叫进取号 - 进取号收到
- Kirk to Enterprise. - Enterprise here.
解除战备警戒
Secure from general quarters...
传送两名，只传送两名警卫过来
...and beam down two, and only two, security guards.
让他们找卢瑞先生报道
Have them report to Mr. Lurry.
批准所有非执勤船员登岸休假
Authorise shore leave for all off-duty personnel.
- 是的，舰长 - 寇克
- Yes, captain. - Kirk out.
寇克舰长，你居然只派遣区区两名警卫
Captain Kirk, how dare you authorise a mere two men
来负责如此重大的项目的安保！
for a project of this importance!
我会报告给星际舰队指挥部
Starfleet Command will hear about this...
我从来都没质疑过任何联邦下达的命令
I have never questioned the orders or the intelligence
或联邦代表的智商
of any representative of the Federation.
直到刚才
Until now.
居然使用一级优先通道调遣星舰
Summoning a starship on a priority A-1 channel
去给什么储藏室做守卫
to guard some storage compartments.
麦子储藏室
Storage compartments of wheat.
不过舰长，克林贡人绝不会乐见
Nevertheless, captain, the Klingons would not enjoy seeing us
我们对舍曼星的成功开发
successfully develop Sherman's Planet.
我觉得也是
I guess not.
休假的时候倒是跑得挺快啊
I see you didn't waste any time taking your shore leave.
我都多久没休过假了？
And how often do I get shore leave?
她想出来购物，我觉得我能帮她参谋参谋
She wants to shop, and I thought I would help her.
不好意思，借过一下
Excuse me. Excuse me.
契科夫，你觉得这是什么？
Mr. Chekov, what do you make of this?
哦，小黑麦
Oh, quadrotriticale.
我在书上见过，但是从来没见过实物
I've read about this, but I've never seen any before.
所有人都认识这个玩意儿吗？
Does everybody know about this wheat but me?
肯定不是大家都认识，舰长，这是俄国人发明的
Well, not everyone, captain. It's a Russian invention.
我什么也不要，我之前怎么说的，现在还是这句话
I don't want any, I told you before, and I'm telling you again.
我不会再要火晶石了
I don't want any more Spican flame gems.
托你的福，我手里的火晶石
Thanks to you, I already have enough Spican flame gems
- 已经够我用一辈子的了 - 真替你难过，我的朋友
- to last me a lifetime. - How sad for you, my friend.
你在别处绝对找不到这么好的石头，不过我还有更好的
You won't find a finer stone anywhere. But I have something better.
你肯定会想要一些
Surely you want some...
安塔利亚发光水
...Antarian glow water.
- 我就是用这个给火晶石抛光的 - 你可真够考究的
- I use that to polish the flame gems. - You're a difficult man to reach.
不过，我从星系边缘带来的这种东西
But I have something from the far reaches of the galaxy.
- 你肯定会想要的 - 绝不会是随你定价
- Surely you want... - Not at your price.
这是什么？是活的吗？
Oh, what is it? Is it alive?
我能摸摸吗？
May I hold it?
它可真可爱啊，这是什么？
Oh, it's adorable. What is it?
这是什么？怎么，美女，这是毛球
What is it? Why, lovely lady, it's a tribble.
毛球？
A tribble?
除了您自己以外
Only the sweetest creature known to man.
人类已知的最可爱的生物
Excepting, of course, your lovely self.
它在发出呼噜呼噜的声音
Oh, it's purring.
你听，它在打呼噜
Listen, it's purring.
它在说它喜欢你
It's only saying that it likes you.
这个你卖吗？
Are you selling them?
我们正打算说这个呢
That's what we're trying to decide right now.
10个信用点这个价格相当合理了，朋友
My friend, 10 credits apiece is a very reasonable price.
你可以自己看看
Now, you can see for yourself
我们这位美女有多喜欢这个小东西
how much the lovely little lady appreciates the finer things.
- 一个信用点一只 - 它不咬人吧？
- One credit apiece. - He won't bite, will he?
长官，星球之间运送危险生物
Sir, transporting harmful animals from one planet to another
是违反法律法规的，你不会不知道吧？
is against regulations, or weren't you aware of that?
况且，毛球没有牙
Besides, tribbles have no teeth.
好吧，我在刚才的价格上翻个番，两个信用点
All right, I'll double my offer. Two credits.
0乘以2还是0
Twice nothing is still nothing.
你要是不要的话，我就买下了，我觉得它好可爱啊
Well, if you're not gonna take him, I'm gonna take him. I think he's cute.
- 四个信用点 - 这是出价呢还是搞笑呢？
- Four credits. - Is that an offer or a joke?
- 出价呢 - 不可能
- That's my offer. - That's a joke.
五个
Five.
我知道你是个实诚人，这么着吧
I can see you're an honest man. I'll tell you what I'm going to do.
我降价到8.5个信用点
I'm going to lessen my price to 8 and a half credits.
你这是不想做这笔生意了，朋友
You're talking yourself out of a deal, friend.
- 6个信用点，不能再加了 - 7.5个
- Six credits, not a credit more. - Seven and a half.
7个？
Seven?
好吧，你这个劫匪，6个信用点
All right, you robber, 6 credits.
- 成交，我什么时候能拿货 - 立等可取
- Done. When can I have them? - Right away.
你准备多少钱卖给我呢？
All right, what are you selling them for?
让我算算，美女，进价是6个信用点
Well, let me see, little lady. It's 6 credits.
算上其它成本利润
I figure a reasonable mark-up for a reasonable profit,
大概是10%的加价，售价的话是10个信用点
say, a 10 percent mark-up. Ten credits.
- 抢匪 - 这只就卖给你了
- Thief. - In fact, I'll sell you this one.
嘿！它偷吃我的谷子
Hey! He's eating my grain.
只卖10个信用点
That'll be 10 credits.
这只是我的样品，所以我说了算
That happens to be my sample, and I'll do with it as I please.
我很高兴把它送给这位美女了
And I please to give it to the lovely little lady here.
- 这不好吧，这样行吗？ - 我坚持
- Oh, I couldn't, could I? - I insist.
你这是干嘛呢，搅乱市场秩序？
What are you trying to do, ruin the market?
一旦这个美女带着这个小不点四处走动
Once this lovely little lady starts to show this precious little darling around,
你进的这些货想留都留不住了
you won't be able to keep up with them.
收到，什么事？
Yes, what is it?
星际舰队信息，舰长，优先通道
Message from Starfleet, captain, priority channel.
- 费兹帕特里克司令请求通话 - 联通视频对话，上尉
- Admiral Fitzpatrick speaking. - Put it on visual, lieutenant.
- 寇克舰长 - 寇克
- Captain Kirk. - Kirk here.
舰长，不用我跟你强调
Captain, it is not necessary to remind you
舍曼星求对联邦的重要性吧
of the importance to the Federation of Sherman's Planet.
赢得这个星球的关键就是谷物，小黑麦
The key to our winning of this planet is the grain, quadrotriticale.
装载的货物必须受到重点保护
The shipment of it must be protected.
从现在起，你必须全力协助配合
Effective immediately, you will render any aid and assistance
巴利斯副部长的一切要求
which Undersecretary Baris may require.
确保谷物的安全以及项目的顺利实施是你的责任
The safety of the grain and the project is your responsibility.
星际舰队完毕
Starfleet out.
真是太好了
Well, that's just lovely.
但这并不完全出乎意料
But not totally unexpected.
- 寇克舰长，寇克舰长 - 我在，上尉，怎么了？
- Captain Kirk. Captain Kirk. - Yes, lieutenant, what is it?
传感器探测到了一艘克林贡战列巡洋舰
Sensors are picking up a Klingon battle cruiser
迅速向空间站方向前进
rapidly closing on the station.
红色警戒，通知卢瑞，我们马上到
Go to red alert, notify Mr. Lurry, we'll be right up.
克林贡战舰在什么位置？
What is the position of the Klingon ship?
距离K-7空间站100公里，悬停不动了
A hundred kilometres off K-7. It's just sitting there.
- 舰长，我联通了卢瑞 - 接通视频
- Captain, I have Mr. Lurry. - Put him on visual.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
卢瑞，有一艘克林贡战舰在距你100公里的位置悬停
Mr. Lurry, there's a Klingon warship hanging 100 kilometres off your station.
我觉得克林贡不是打算攻击我们
I don't think the Klingons are planning to attack us.
为什么？
Why not?
因为克林贡战舰的舰长
Because at this moment, the captain of the Klingon ship
现在正坐在我的办公室里
is sitting right here in my office.
红色警戒解除，把我们传送过去
Cancel red alert. We'll beam right down.
保安部，解除红色警戒
Security, cancel red alert.
舰长日志，星历4524.2
Captain's log, stardate 4524.2.
克林贡战舰就悬停在距离
A Klingon warship is hovering only 100 kilometres
K7深空空间站100公里远的地方
from Deep Space Station K-7
而战舰的舰长却出现在太空站负责人的办公室里
while its captain waits in the station manager's office.
不知道他们又打算干什么
Their intentions are unknown.
- 我亲爱的寇克舰长 - 我亲爱的克洛斯舰长
- My dear Captain Kirk. - My dear Captain Koloth.
我保证我们是为了和平而来的
Let me assure you that my intentions are peaceful.
就像我刚才跟卢瑞说的那样
As I've already told Mr. Lurry,
我们出现在这里是为了休登岸假
the purpose of my presence here is to invoke shore-leave rights.
休假？
Shore leave?
舰长，我们克林贡人不像你们地球人那么心思细密
Captain, we Klingons are not as luxury-minded as you Earthers.
我们的船舰上不会配备，怎么说来的？
We do not equip our ships with, how shall I say it?
非必需品
Non-essentials.
我们已经在太空里航行5个月了
We have been in space for five months
决定以什么方式放松，纯粹是我们的私事儿
and what we choose as recreation is our own business.
还有一点我要补充，根据Organian和平条约
I might also add that under the terms of the Organian Peace Treaty,
你们不能拒绝我们的要求
you cannot refuse us.
说得对，这事儿不归我管
Yes, well, I don't make those decisions.
卢瑞是负责这些事情的人
Mr. Lurry is in charge of those matters.
舰长，能借一步说话吗？
Captain, may I speak to you a minute?
寇克，我不想让他们在这儿，但是我也没有权力拒绝他们
Kirk, I don't want them here, but I don't have the authority to refuse.
我有相应的权力，正好派上用场
Well, I have the authority to act, and I'm gonna use it.
我亲爱的克洛斯舰长
My dear Captain Koloth,
你可能的确可以带着你的人过来休登岸假
you may indeed bring your men down on shore leave.
但是一次只能12个人
But only 12 at a time,
而且我可以向你保证，你带过来的每一个人
and I assure you that for every man you bring down here,
都会有一个我安排的保安贴身保护，绝没有安全隐患
I shall have one security guard. There'll be no trouble.
寇克舰长，我们双方各自的政府
Captain Kirk, there's been no formal declaration of hostilities
对外并没有正式的敌对声明
between our two respective governments.
所以自然而然的，我们之间的关系也是和平共处的
So naturally, our relationship will be a peaceful one.
那就让我们共同维系这一平稳现状吧
Let us both take steps to keep it that way.
当然
Of course.
- 又一份技术杂志，史考特？ - 是的
- Another technical journal, Scotty? - Aye.
- 你就从来没有放松过吗？ - 我正在休息
- Don't you ever relax? - I am relaxing.
这东西你养多久了，上尉？
How long have you had that thing, lieutenant?
昨天开始养的，医生
Since yesterday, doctor.
今天早上我发现他，我是说，她有宝宝了
This morning I found out that he... I mean, she had had babies.
你这次可是占便宜了
Well, I'd say in that case you got a bargain.
- 你这儿开托儿所呢，上尉？ - 舰长
- You running a nursery, lieutenant? - Oh, captain.
我完全没这个想法，长官，但是毛球看上去好像另有想法
Well, I hadn't intended to, sir, but the tribble had other plans.
- 你是从空间站弄来的这个？ - 是的，长官
- Did you get this at the space station? - Yes, sir.
非常古怪的生物，舰长
A most curious creature, captain.
它发出的颤音，对人类的神经系统
Its trilling seems to have a tranquilizing effect
有镇定安抚的效果
on the human nervous system.
幸运的是，显然，我对这种形式免疫
Fortunately, of course, I am immune to its effect.
介意我拿一只回实验室研究一下结构吗？
Do you mind if I take one of these to the lab to see what makes it tick?
当然可以，医生，但是如果你打算解剖它
Well, all right, doctor, but if you're gonna dissect it,
我可一点儿都不想知道
I don't want to know about it.
我保证不会伤害它一根头发，不管它头在哪儿
I won't harm a hair on its head, wherever that is.
上尉，既然你打算把它们送人，我能要一只吗？
Say, lieutenant, seeing as you're giving them away, can I have one?
当然可以，我觉得它们已经成年了
Sure, why not? I think they're old enough.
都来拿吧
Go ahead.
舰桥呼叫寇克舰长
Bridge to Captain Kirk.
寇克
Kirk here.
巴利斯通过A频道等待与您通话，长官
Mr. Baris is waiting on channel A to speak to you, sir.
转到这里，契科夫
Pipe it down here, will you, Mr. Chekov?
是，长官，正在接通巴利斯
Aye, sir. Mr. Baris is coming on.
巴利斯，有什么可以效劳的？
Yes, Mr. Baris, what can I do for you?
寇克，空间站里蜂拥而来的都是克林贡人
Kirk, this station is swarming with Klingons.
巴利斯，我不知道12个克林贡人居然可以称之为一大群
I was not aware, Mr. Baris, that 12 Klingons constitutes a swarm.
寇克舰长，空间站里有克林贡士兵
Captain Kirk, there are Klingon soldiers on this station.
我现在需要你确保谷物的安全
Now, I want you to keep that grain safe.
巴利斯，我已经派了警卫在谷物周边了
Mr. Baris, I have guards around the grain,
我也派了警卫贴身跟着克林贡人
I have guards around the Klingons.
这些警卫在那儿驻守的唯一理由，是因为这是星际舰队的要求
The only reason those guards are there is because Starfleet wants them there.
至于你的要求
As for what you want...
已经收到并会记录在日志中的，寇克完毕
...it has been noted and logged. Kirk out.
舰长，我能问问你打算去哪儿吗？
Captain, may I ask where you'll be?
医务室，我头疼
Sickbay, with a headache.
吉姆
Hi, Jim.
老骨头，头疼有什么办法解决吗？
Bones, what have you got for a headache?
我猜猜啊，是因为克林贡还是巴利斯
Let me guess, the Klingons. Baris.
两者都有
Both.
乌呼拉给了你几只？
Hey, how many of these did Uhura give you?
- 就一只 - 但是现在你有十一只
- Just one. - But you've got 11.
你也发现了，哈？
You noticed that, huh?
给你，这个应该管用
Here, this ought to take care of it.
他们怎么那个？他们怎么那什么？
How do they? How do they?
我还没弄明白呢
I haven't figured that out yet.
但是我可以告诉你
But I can tell you this much.
这个东西大概50%的新陈代谢用来繁殖
Almost 50 percent of the creature's metabolism is geared for reproduction.
你知道如果给毛球喂好多吃的会变成什么样吗？
Do you know what you get if you feed a tribble too much?
变成一个胖毛球
A fat tribble.
不是，是变出一大堆饥肠辘辘的小毛球
No, you get a whole bunch of hungry little tribbles.
老骨头，我唯一能给出的建议就是
Well, Bones, all I can suggest...
你干脆开个产科病房得了
...is you open up a maternity ward.
所有休登岸假的人最好集体行动
I want all you men who are going on shore leave to stay in groups.
避免与克林贡人发生冲突
Avoid trouble with the Klingons.
他们休假前我会再说一遍的，长官
I'll tell them before they go, sir.
你不休登岸假吗，史考特？
Aren't you going on shore leave, Scotty?
- 不休，长官 - 我要求你休登岸假
- Oh, no, sir. - I want you to go on shore leave.
确保所有人都别惹麻烦
Make sure that everybody stays out of trouble.
但是，舰长
But, captain...
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
史考特，好好玩儿
Scotty, enjoy yourself.
朋友，你要不要来一个可爱的小毛球啊？
Friend, can I offer you a charming little tribble?
- 不要，谢谢 - 也许这两位先生想要一只？
- No, thanks. - Perhaps one of you other gents?
克林贡朋友！看看这个温柔的小毛球，你们感不感兴趣？
Friend Klingon! Can I interest you in a harmless little tribble?
拿走
Get it away from me.
对不起，我不知道怎么了
I'm sorry, I can't understand it.
他们从来没这样过
I've never seen them act this way before.
带着你的虫子赶紧走
Get out of here with that parasite.
- 他就是个温柔的小 - 把它拿走！
- He's only a harmless little... - Take it away!
好的
Yes.
我的好朋友！
My good friend!
你觉得咱们再做笔买卖怎么样？
How would you like to enter another little transaction?
- 这次，一个小不点儿毛球 - 一个毛球？
- This time, a tribble for a spot of... - A tribble?
毛球？
Tribble?
毛球
Tribble.
你什么时候能断奶啊，小家伙？
When are you going to get off that milk diet, lad?
这是伏特加
This is vodka.
在我家乡你喝的那个就是苏打水，这个才是男人喝的
Where I come from, that's soda pop. Now, this is a drink for a man.
- 苏格兰威士忌？ - 是的
- Scotch? - Aye.
这是列宁格勒的一个老太太发明的
It was invented by a little old lady from Leningrad.
地球人就喜欢这些毛茸茸的东西，哈？
The Earthers like those fuzzy things, don't they?
是阿
Why, yes.
实话实说，我从来都不喜欢地球人
Well, frankly, I never liked Earthers.
他们让我想起瑞格利的血蠕虫
They remind me of Regulan blood worms.
- 真是受够了 - 别激动，小伙子
- That does it. - Easy, lad.
你应当要更宽容才对
You ought to be more forgiving.
我想起来了
I just remembered.
有一个地球人，他和那些血蠕虫不一样
There is one Earth man who doesn't remind me of a Regulan blood worm.
那个人是寇克
That's Kirk.
瑞格利血蠕虫是那种软趴趴没骨头的生物
A Regulan blood worm is soft and shapeless.
但是寇克不是软骨头
But Kirk isn't soft.
也许寇克是一个神气活现傲慢无礼的
Kirk may be a swaggering, overbearing,
铁皮独裁者，满脑子都是些神圣的幻想
tin-plated dictator with delusions of godhood...
但他不是软骨头
...but he's not soft.
别激动，孩子
Take it easy, lad.
每个人都有权发表观点
Everybody's entitled to an opinion.
没错
That's right.
如果我认为寇克
And if I think that Kirk
就是个迪泥比烂泥怪
is a Denebian slime devil,
那仍然是我的看法
well, that's my opinion too.
别动手，这是命令
Don't do it, mister, and that's an order.
但是你听见他都说舰长什么了
But you heard what he called the captain.
别当回事儿，这不值得动手打架
Forget it. It's not worth fighting for.
我们已经是成年人了，这点儿废话不算什么
We're big enough to take a few insults.
喝你的酒
Now drink your drink.
当然，我还得说寇克舰长和他的船还是挺配的
Of course, I'd say that Captain Kirk deserves his ship.
我们喜欢进取号
We like the Enterprise.
真心喜欢
We really do.
那个松松垮垮生锈的桶看上去就像是个垃圾船
That sagging old rust bucket is designed like a garbage scow.
半个象限的人都这么认为
Half the quadrant knows it.
这就是为什么他们要学习克林贡语
That's why they're learning to speak Klingonee!
史考特
Mr. Scott.
伙计，你这个措辞欠考虑吧？
Laddie, don't you think you should rephrase that?
你说的对，的确
You're right, I should.
我不应该说进取号应该去收垃圾
I didn't mean to say that the Enterprise should be hauling garbage.
我想说进取号其实就是一坨垃圾
I meant to say that it should be hauled away as garbage.
舰长日志，星历4525.6
Captain's log, stardate 4525.6.
克林贡船员和进取号船员
A small disturbance between the Klingon crew
在K-7空间站
and members of the Enterprise crew
发生了一起小规模冲突
has broken out aboard Space Station K-7.
我只能强制取消双方的登岸假
I am forced to cancel shore leave for both ships.
我想知道谁挑的头，我等着呢
I want to know who started it. I'm waiting.
弗里曼，谁先动的手
Freeman, who started the fight?
- 我不知道，长官 - 好吧
- I don't know, sir. - All right.
契科夫
Chekov.
我了解你，是你先动的手，对不对？
I know you. You started it, didn't you?
- 不是，长官，不是我 - 那么，是谁？
- No, sir, I didn't. - Well, who did?
- 我不知道，长官 - “我不知道，长官”
- I don't know, sir. - "I don't know, sir."
我想知道谁打的第一拳
I want to know who threw the first punch.
你们都回到寝室关禁闭，直到我找出第一个动手的人
You're all confined to quarters until I find out who started it.
解散
Dismissed.
史考特，你不用去
Scotty, not you.
你应该试图阻止冲突的，史考特
You were supposed to prevent trouble, Mr. Scott.
是，舰长
Aye, captain.
谁最先动的手，史考特？
Who threw the first punch, Scotty?
史考特？
Scotty?
- 是我，舰长 - 是你，史考特？
- I did, captain. - You did, Mr. Scott?
- 因为什么，史考特？ - 他们侮辱我们，长官
- What caused it, Scotty? - They insulted us, sir.
- 看来骂得挺狠的阿 - 确实是
- Must have been some insult. - Aye, it was.
- 你先动的手 - 是
- You threw the first punch. - Aye.
契科夫想动手来的，我阻止了他
Chekov wanted to, but I held him back.
你阻止？
You held..?
为什么契科夫想动手？
Why did Chekov want to start a fight?
那些克林贡人，呃，我说的不会记录在案吧？
Well, the Klingons... Is this off the record?
是，这些都不会留记录的
No, this is not off the record.
舰长，克林贡人说你
Well, captain, Klingons called you...
是个裹着铁皮傲慢无礼的独裁者
...a tin-plated, overbearing, swaggering dictator
- 满脑子胡思乱想 - 就这些？
- with delusions of godhood. - Is that all?
不止，长官，他们还拿你和Denebian烂泥怪相提并论
No, sir, they also compared you with a Denebian slime devil.
- 我知道了 - 然后他们还说
- I see. - And then they said that...
- 我能想象的到，史考特 - 是，长官
- I get the picture, Scotty. - Yes, sir.
他们说完这些你就开始揍克林贡人了？
And after they said all this, that's when you hit the Klingons?
- 没有，长官 - 没有？
- No, sir. - No?
那会儿我还没动手
No, I didn't.
你告诉我们尽量避免冲突
You told us to avoid trouble.
是的
Oh, yes.
我觉得这也不值得打一架
And I didn't see that it was worth fighting about.
我们已经是成年人了，这点儿废话不算什么
After all, we're big enough to take a few insults.
是吧？
Aren't we?
他们到底说什么了才导致你们开始打架的？
What was it they said that started the fight?
他们管进取号叫垃圾船！
They called the Enterprise a garbage scow!
长官
Sir.
我明白了
I see.
然后你就打了克林贡人
And that's when you hit the Klingon.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
你打克林贡人是因为他们侮辱了进取号
You hit the Klingons because they insulted the Enterprise,
不是因为他们
not because they?
长官，这事关脸面
Well, sir, this was a matter of pride.
明白了，史考特，解散
All right, Scotty. Dismissed.
史考特，在没有新的指令前你回寝室关禁闭吧
Scotty, you're restricted to quarters until further notice.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
多谢你，长官
Thank you, sir.
我终于有时间可以把那本技术杂志看完了
That'll give me a chance to catch up on my technical journals.
怎么了，史波克？
What's the matter, Spock?
这些生物让人觉得不安
There's something disquieting about these creatures.
- 别跟我说你喜欢上他们了 - 别侮辱我，医生
- Don't tell me you've got a feeling. - Don't be insulting, doctor.
他们让我想起了田间的野百合
They remind me of the lilies of the field.
“他们既不辛苦，也不操劳”（马太福音6：28）
"They toil not, neither do they spin."
但他们吃的一点儿不少
But they seem to eat a great deal.
我看不出他们有什么实质用途
I see no practical use for them.
难道任何东西对你而言都必须有什么实质用途吗？
Does everything have to have a practical use for you?
他们可爱，软乎乎，毛绒绒
They're nice, they're soft, and they're furry,
而且他们的叫声让人觉得心情愉快
and they make a pleasant sound.
就跟貂绒小提琴一样没用，医生，我看不出养这个有什么用
So would an ermine violin, doctor, but I see no advantage in having one.
喜欢小动物是人类的天性
It is a human characteristic to love little animals,
特别是他们在某些方面特别可爱呢
especially if they're attractive in some way.
医生，我对人类的天性非常了解
Doctor, I am well aware of human characteristics,
我经常被这些天性所扰
I am frequently inundated by them,
但是我已经训练自己不受这些影响
but I have trained myself to put up with practically anything.
史波克，我对这些小毛球还不太了解
Spock, I don't know too much about these little tribbles yet
但是我发现一件事
but there is one thing that I have discovered.
- 是什么，医生？ - 我喜欢他们
- What is that, doctor? - I like them.
胜过我喜欢你
Better than I like you.
- 医生 - 什么？
- Doctor. - Yes?
他们的确有一个优点
They do, indeed, have one redeeming characteristic.
- 是什么？ - 他们没那么絮叨
- What's that? - They do not talk too much.
我先告退了，长官
If you'll excuse me, sir.
麦考伊医生，你能来舰桥一下吗？
Dr. McCoy, would you mind coming up to the Bridge?
乌呼拉上尉，这些毛球是怎么跑到舰桥上来的？
Lieutenant Uhura, how did all these tribbles get on the Bridge?
我不知道，长官， 他们现在几乎满船舰都是
I don't know, sir. They do seem to be all over the ship.
- 麦考伊医生 - 怎么？你要见我，吉姆？
- Dr. McCoy. - Yes? Did you want to see me, Jim?
别看我，是毛球自己繁殖的
Well, don't look at me, it's the tribbles who are breeding.
要是我们不把它们弄下船，很快他们就要多到齐腰深了
And if we don't get them off this ship, we'll be hip deep in them.
解释一下？
Would you explain that?
我能想到的最可能的解释就是，他们生出来的时候就已经怀孕了
Well, the nearest thing I can figure out is that they're born pregnant.
这种做法倒是挺省时间的
Which seems to be quite a time saver.
我知道，但是怎么
I know, but really...
而且据我观察
And from my observations,
他们是雌雄同体的，可以随意繁殖
it seems they're bisexual, reproducing at will.
他们繁殖意愿强烈啊
And, brother, have they got a lot of will.
舰长，我不得不同意医生的看法
Captain, I am forced to agree with the doctor.
我尝试计算它们的繁殖速率
I've been running computations on their rate of reproduction.
数据可怕的惊人
The figures are taking an alarming direction.
他们在消耗我们的补给，然后没给我们任何回报
They are consuming our supplies and returning nothing.
但是它们的确给予了我们，史波克，它们给了我们爱
But they do give us something, Mr. Spock, they give us love.
西拉诺·琼斯说，毛球是唯一可以用钱买到的爱
Well, Cyrano Jones says that a tribble is the only love that money can buy.
但太多了也受不了
Too much of anything, lieutenant, even love,
上尉，即使是爱
isn't necessarily a good thing.
是的，舰长
Yes, captain.
通知养护队清理整个船
Get a maintenance crew to clean up the entire ship.
告诉卢瑞我现在传送过去
And then contact Mr. Lurry and tell him I'm beaming down.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
找到西拉诺·琼斯，然后拘捕他
Have him find Cyrano Jones and hold him.
把这些毛球从舰桥上弄下去
And get these tribbles off the Bridge.
是的，舰长
Aye, aye, captain.
寇克舰长，你的语气让我感到困惑
Captain Kirk, I'm mystified at your tone of voice.
我没干什么违法乱纪的事儿啊
I've done nothing to warrant such severe treatment.
哦，是吗？
Oh, really?
你肯定已经意识到了
Surely you must have realised what would happen
如果你把毛球从满是捕食者的环境中
if you removed the tribbles from their predator-filled environment
转移到过度繁殖不受限制的环境下
into an environment where their natural multiplicative proclivities
会是什么结果吧？
would have no restraining factors.
当然，你说什么？
Well, of cour... What did you say?
把毛球从它们适应的环境中带出来
By removing the tribbles from their natural habitat,
就好比说，拔掉瓶塞
you have, so to speak, removed the cork from the bottle
释放精灵一样的后果
and allowed the genie to escape.
你是说它们繁殖过快吗？
Well, if by that you mean, do they breed quickly?
当然，我用这种方法来保持库存
Well, of course, that's how I maintain my stock.
但是动物繁殖并没有违反任何法律法规
But breeding animals is not against regulations,
只有繁殖危险物种才是禁止的
only breeding dangerous ones.
- 毛球并不是危险物种 - 但是它繁殖速率高的不可置信
- And tribbles are not dangerous. - Just incredibly prolific.
说的没错，6个信用点购买一只
Precisely. And at 6 credits a head...
然后，它就变成了一大堆
Well, that is, a body... it mounts up.
要是没别的事儿我就先走了
Now, if you'll excuse me.
你应该在销售的时候配上维护手册
You ought to sell an instruction and maintenance manual with this thing.
如果我这么做了，人们怎么满足自己的求知欲呢？
If I did, what would happen to man's search for knowledge?
我得回去照顾我得船了
Well, I must be tending my ship.
直接说吧，长官，告诉他们
Go ahead, sir, tell him.
寇克舰长，我觉得你所谓的安保措施就是个笑话
Captain Kirk, I consider your security measures a disgrace.
在我看来，你对这个重中之重的项目太不当回事儿了
In my opinion, you have taken this entire very important project too lightly.
正相反，先生，我认为这个项目非常的重要
On the contrary, sir, I think of this project as very important.
我只是不拿你当回事儿罢了
It is you I take lightly.
我会向有关当局详细全面的汇报这些的
I am going to report fully, to the proper authorities,
你居然允许一个极有可能是克林贡间谍的人
that you have given free and complete access to this station
在这艘船舰上进出自由
to a man who is quite probably a Klingon agent.
这可是非常严重的指控，你说的那个人是谁？
That's a very serious charge. To whom are you referring?
就是刚才从这儿走出去的那个人
To that man who just walked out of here.
西拉诺·琼斯？克林贡间谍？
Cyrano Jones? A Klingon agent?
- 我说过了 - 我听见了
- You heard me. - I heard you.
他只是不能相信他耳朵所听到的内容
He simply could not believe his ears.
你有什么的证据质控琼斯吗？
What evidence do you have against Mr. Jones?
我的助手已经严密监视琼斯先生
My assistant here has kept Mr. Jones
相当长一段时间了
under close surveillance for quite some time,
他的行为非常的可疑
and his actions have been most suspicious.
我认为他曾卷入你的手下上次的那起冲突
I believe he was involved in that little altercation between your men...
嗯，继续，你还有什么别的证据？
Yes, yes, go on. What else do you have?
舰长，我查看了他的航行日志
Well, captain, I checked his ship's log
数据显示他曾经在克林贡的势力范围内
and it seems that he was within the Klingons' sphere of influence
停留了至少四个月的时间
less than four months ago.
这个人就是个独立的侦查员，舰长
The man is an independent scout, captain.
他很有可能也是克林贡的间谍
It's quite possible that he is also a Klingon spy.
我们已经对西拉诺·琼斯进行了详细的背景调查
We have already checked on the background of Mr. Cyrano Jones.
他持有行星间测绘和勘探执照
He is a licensed asteroid locator and prospector.
目前为止几乎没有任何违法行为
He's never broken the law, at least not severely,
在过去的这七年时间里，他驾驶着他的单人飞船
and for the past seven years, with his one-man spaceship,
靠着倒买倒卖紧俏货品，当然，也包括毛球
he has obtained a marginal living by engaging in the buying and selling
来勉强维持生计
of rare merchandise, including, unfortunately, tribbles.
- 但是他一直盯着我的那些谷物！ - 你有证据证明这些吗？
- But he is after my grain! - Do you have any proof of that?
你不能否认他扰乱了这个空间站秩序
You can't deny he's disrupted this station.
扰乱空间站秩序的人，但不是克林贡间谍
People have disrupted stations before without being Klingon agents.
巴利斯，这就是欲加之罪
Sometimes all they need is a title, Mr. Baris.
不幸的是，扰乱空间站秩序不是违法行为
Unfortunately, disrupting a space station is not an offence.
现在，不好意思，我还要回去照顾我的飞船
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have a ship to tend to.
我的鸡肉三明治和咖啡
My chicken sandwich and coffee.
这就是我的鸡肉三明治和咖啡
This is my chicken sandwich and coffee.
有意思
Fascinating.
我要把这些东西弄下船
I want these things off the ship.
我不管是不是需要全员出动，我就是要把这些东西弄下船
I don't care if it takes every man, I want them off the ship.
是的，他们跑到机械室去了
Aye, they're into the machinery, all right.
估计他们也跑到食物处理系统里去了
And they're probably in all the other food processors too.
- 怎么进去的？ - 估计是通过通风管道
- How? - Probably through one of the air vents.
舰长，这种通风管道空间站里也有
Captain, there are vents of that type on the space station.
储藏室里也有
And in the storage compartments.
这里是寇克，跟负责人卢瑞和尼兹·巴利斯联系
This is Kirk. Contact Manager Lurry and Nilz Baris.
让他们和我们在最近的储藏室会合，我们马上传送过去
Have them meet us near the storage compartments. We're beaming down.
快走，史波克
Come on, Spock.
传送
Energize.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我要是没猜错，估计出大事儿了
Plenty, if what I think happened has happened.
- 警卫，这扇门安全吗？ - 是的，长官，没有东西能进入
- Guard, is that door secure? - Yes, sir, nothing could get in.
很好，打开它
Good. Open it.
打不开，长官，好像卡住了
It's not working, sir. It seems to be stuck.
让我试试
Here, let me try.
他们看起来大吃了一顿啊
They seem to be gorged.
大吃一顿？在我的谷堆里？
Gorged? On my grain?
寇克，你要为此负责人
Kirk, I am going to hold you responsible.
- 这肯定有上千只 - 得有十万只了
- There must be thousands of them. - Hundreds of thousands.
1,771,561只
1,771,561.
这是在假设一只毛球一窝生10只
That's assuming one tribble, multiplying with an average litter of ten,
在三天里每12小时就繁殖一代
producing a new generation every 12 hours, over a period of three days.
这个数量也仅是基于他们三天前进来的假设
And that's assuming that they got here three days ago.
同时还要考虑到谷物的存量是否充足
And allowing for the amount of grain consumed
以及储藏室的空间是否足够
and the volume of the storage compartment.
寇克，你应该知道！
Kirk, you should have known!
是你把这么个有前景的项目
You are responsible for turning the development project
变成了现在这么一团糟的！
into a total disaster!
- 巴利斯 - 我受够了被你威胁了
- Mr. Baris... - And I am through being intimidated.
你侮辱我，你忽视我
Now, you have insulted me, you have ignored me,
你完全不搭理我！
you've walked all over me!
你滥用职权，你驳回了我的提议
You have abused your authority, and you have rejected my requests.
这个！这就是下场！
And this! This is the result.
我要让你对此负全责，寇克
I am going to hold you responsible, Kirk.
巴利斯，你要是再不闭嘴我就把你关起来
Mr. Baris, I'll hold you in irons if you don't shut up.
吉姆，我想我找到解决方法了
Jim, I think I've got it.
只要停止喂食就行了
All we have to do is quit feeding them.
我们停止喂食，它们就不再繁殖了
We quit feeding them, they stop breeding.
现在他才告诉我
Now he tells me.
舰长，这个毛球死了
Captain, this tribble is dead.
这些也是
And so are these.
这里大部分都死了
A lot of them are dead.
还有一部分是活的，但是也活不了多久了
A lot of them are alive, but they won't be for long.
符合逻辑的推测是，谷物里面掺有什么东西使它们死亡
A logical assumption is that there is something in the grain.
没错，老骨头，我希望你对这些毛球，谷物以及其余都进行分析
Yes. Bones, I want the tribbles, the grain, everything analysed.
我想知道是什么弄死了这些毛球
I wanna know what killed these tribbles.
我还没弄明白怎么让它们活下去呢
I haven't figured out what keeps them alive yet.
好吧，要是有发现我就通知你
All right, if I find out anything, I'll let you know.
你这么做也于事无补，寇克
That isn't gonna do you any good, Kirk.
这个项目已经被毁了，星际舰队马上就会收到消息
This project is ruined, and Starfleet is gonna hear about it.
他们听说后就会组织听证会
And when they do, they will have a board of enquiry
他们一定会烧死你的
and they will roast you alive.
我到时候一定会到场的，寇克，我会充分享受你所受的折磨
And I am gonna be there, Kirk, to enjoy every minute of it.
在听证会前我还始终是舰长
Until that board of enquiry, I'm still the captain.
作为舰长，我要求马上完成两件事
And as captain, I want two things done.
第一，找到西拉诺·琼斯，第二
First, find Cyrano Jones, and second...
把这扇门关上
...close that door.
寇克舰长，你们对我的这种态度我表示抗议
Really, Captain Kirk, I must protest this treatment!
琼斯先生
Mr. Jones, with an armful.
- 只是问几个问题 - 寇克舰长！
- A few questions. - Captain Kirk!
你又要干嘛？
Yes, what do you want?
需要你们给克林贡指挥部发一个官方的道歉
An official apology, addressed to the Klingon High Command.
我要求你对在这个象限里
I expect you to assume full responsibility
克林贡人所造成的骚扰负全责
for the persecution of Klingon nationals in this quadrant.
道歉？
An apology?
没错，你骚扰了我的人，你对待他们就像对待犯人一样
Yes. You've harassed my men. You've treated them like criminals.
你简直粗鲁至极，寇克舰长
You've been most uncourteous, Captain Kirk.
如果你打算避免外交争端
Now, if you wish to avoid a diplomatic incident...
不行，寇克，你不能让他如意
No, Kirk, you can't let him.
他们会以此为理由借机占据舍曼星球
That will give them the wedge they need to claim Sherman's Planet.
克林贡指挥官气势汹汹的样子
I believe that more than the word of an aggrieved Klingon commander
已经非常清楚地昭示了他的用心了，巴利斯
would be necessary for that, Mr. Baris.
史波克，就舍曼星的所属权问题
Mr. Spock, as far as Sherman's Planet is concerned,
寇克舰长已经给了我们足够的借口了
Captain Kirk has already given it to us.
那我们走着瞧
Well, we'll see about that.
在我采取任何正式行动之前，我想弄清楚到底发生了什么
But before I take any official action, I'd like to know just what happened.
谁把毛球弄到小黑麦仓库里的
Who put the tribbles in the quadrotriticale,
谷物里面什么东西把毛球弄死了？
and what was in the grain that killed them?
寇克舰长，你在弄这些之前，我能要求件事儿吗？
Captain Kirk, before you go on, may I make a request?
说吧
Yes.
你能把这些东西弄走吗？
Can you get those things out of here?
- 有意思 - 等一下
- Remarkable. - Hold on a minute.
我记得你说过毛球几乎喜欢所有人
I thought you said tribbles liked everybody.
是阿，我也不明白这是怎么了
Well, they do. I can't understand it.
上次我看见毛球这么大反应是那天在酒吧里
The last time I saw one act this way was at the bar.
- 酒吧里有什么？ - 克林贡人，他，那个人
- What was in the bar? - Klingons. Him, for one.
你说得对，琼斯，他们确实不喜欢克林贡人
You're right, Mr. Jones. They don't like Klingons.
但是它们喜欢瓦肯星人
But they do like Vulcans.
为什么，史波克？想不到你还挺讨喜
Why, Mr. Spock, I didn't know you had it in you.
显然，毛球是感知非常敏锐的生物，舰长
Obviously, tribbles are very perceptive creatures, captain.
显然是
Obviously.
巴利斯，它们居然喜欢你
Mr. Baris, they like you.
它们倒是不挑食
Well, there's no accounting for taste.
它们不喜欢你，达尔文，我很好奇这是为什么
They don't like you, Mr. Darvin. I wonder why.
老骨头？
Bones?
心跳完全不对
Heartbeat is all wrong.
他的体温是
His body temperature is...
吉姆，这是个克林贡人
Jim, this man is a Klingon.
克林贡人？
A Klingon?
我在想星际指挥部会对此作何感想
I wonder what Starfleet Command will say about that.
谷子什么情况，老骨头？
What about the grain, Bones?
- 里面馋了毒药 - 毒药？
- Oh, yes. It was poisoned. - Poisoned?
对，里面被渗透进了一种病毒
Yes, it's been impregnated with a virus.
病毒在血流中转化成一种惰性物质
The virus turns into an inert material in the bloodstream,
生物吃的越多，惰性物质累积就越多
and the more the organism eats, the more inert matter is built up.
两到三天之后会达到一个峰值
So after two or three days it would reach a point
这之后将导致无法摄取足够生存的营养
where they couldn't take in enough nourishment to survive.
从而活活被饿死
They starved to death.
在整整一贮藏室的谷堆里，它们被活活饿死了
In a storage compartment full of grain, they starved to death.
基本就是这样的
That is essentially it.
- 达尔文，你有什么要说的吗？ - 我没什么可解释的
- Mr. Darvin, you want to talk? - I have nothing to say.
好吧！是我在谷物里面放的毒药，把它们拿走
All right! I poisoned the grain, take them away.
毛球和这件事无关？
The tribbles had nothing to do with it?
我不清楚，我以前从来没见过这种东西
I don't know, I never saw one before,
我再也不想看见这种毛绒绒的怪物了
and I hope I never see one of those fuzzy, miserable things again.
我会给你好好安排的，达尔文
I'm certain that can be arranged, Darvin.
警卫
Guards.
请容我告退，舰长
If you'll excuse me, captain.
克林贡舰长，关于你提到的那个道歉
Captain Koloth, about that apology.
怎么？
Yes?
给你们6个小时的时间，带着你们的船舰离开星际联邦星域
You have six hours to get your ship out of Federation territory.
我觉得，我已经开始喜欢上毛球了
Hey, you know, I think I could learn to like tribbles.
舰长，我现在可以走了吧
Well, captain, I suppose I'm free to go now.
不行，你还不能走，我有点儿东西给你看看
No, you're not. There's something I want to show you.
你知道倒卖对人类生命有威胁
Do you know what the penalty is
的动物要受到什么样的惩罚吗？
for transporting an animal proven harmful to human life?
舰长，一个小小的毛球是完全无害的
Captain, one little tribble isn't harmful.
舰长，你不会这么对我的，是吧？
Captain, you wouldn't do a thing like that to me, now, would you?
不会吧？
Would you?
惩罚措施就是劳教改造20年
The penalty is 20 years in a rehabilitation colony.
寇克舰长，我的朋友！好朋友寇克
Captain Kirk... Friend! Friend Kirk.
我相信我们之间能够互相体谅
Surely we can come to some sort of mutual understanding.
毕竟，毛球帮你们发现了谷物里面被放了毒药
After all, my tribbles did put you wise to the poisoned grain
还帮你们甄别出了克林贡的卧底
and they did help you to find the Klingon agent.
我们这次可是通过毛球拯救了很多人的生命呢
We saved a lot of lives that way.
- 有一件事儿你可以办到 - 定当尽力
- There is one thing you can do. - Yes.
把空间站里的每一只毛球都抓走
Pick up every tribble on the space station.
如果你做到了，我就去跟卢瑞商量，把你的船舰还给你
If you do that, I'll speak to Mr. Lurry about returning your spaceship.
这得花上好几年呢
It would take years.
确切的说需要17.9年
Seventeen-point-nine, to be exact.
17.9年？
Seventeen-point-nine years?
有得就有失嘛
Consider it job security.
舰长，你太不近人情了，好吧，好吧
Captain, you're a hard man. All right, all right!
- 你愿意干吗？ - 他会愿意的
- You'll do it? - He'll do it.
我愿意做
I'll do it.
舰长，星际舰队会把污染的货船送走
Captain, Starfleet was able to divert that freighter.
太好了，这就意味着舍曼星
Good, that means Sherman's Planet will get its quadrotriticale
只是晚几个星期就能拿到小黑麦了
only a few weeks late.
这儿一只毛球都没有了
I don't see any tribbles around here.
你在整艘船舰上也不会看见任何毛球了
And you won't find a tribble on this entire ship.
老骨头，你是怎么做到的？
Bones, how'd you do that?
我可不能抢了别人的功劳
Well, I cannot take credit for another man's work.
- 斯考特做到的 - 斯考特！
- Scotty did it. - Scotty!
毛球去哪儿了？
Where are the tribbles?
舰长，其实这些都是在史波克的建议下做的
Captain, it was really Mr. Spock's recommendation.
那是自然，史波克？
Of course. Spock?
根据计算机对数据的分析
Based on computer analysis, of course,
当然，也算上了相应的各种可能
taking into account the possibilities of...
先生们，我不想打断你们的互相吹捧
Gentlemen, I don't want to interrupt this mutual-admiration society,
但是我就是想知道毛球到底在哪儿
but I'd like to know where the tribbles are.
告诉他，史波克
Tell him, Spock.
斯考特完成了相应的技术操作
Well, it was Mr. Scott who performed the actual engineering.
斯考特
Mr. Scott.
毛球到底去哪儿了？
Where are the tribbles?
我使用了传送室，舰长
I used the transporter, captain.
- 你使用了传送室？ - 是的
- You used the transporter? - Aye.
你把它们都传送去哪儿了？
Well, where did you transport them?
斯考特，你不会把它们扔进太空了吧？
Scott, you didn't transport them into space, did you?
寇克舰长，这也太没人性了！
Captain Kirk, that would be inhuman!
- 那它们去哪儿了？ - 我给它们找了个好地儿
- Well, where are they? - I gave them a very good home.
- 在哪儿？ - 我把它们传送给克林贡人了，长官
- Where? - I gave them to the Klingons, sir.
- 你把它们传送给克林贡人了？ - 是的，长官
- You gave them to the Klingons? - Aye, sir.
在他们进入到曲速以前
Before they went into warp,
我把整堆的毛球传送到它们轮机室去了
I transported the whole kit and caboodle to their Engine Room,
在那里它们将会大展拳脚
where they'll be no tribble at all.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF微博http://weibo.com/tlfsubs/
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/